Dan Zervoudakes

Denver, Colorado 609.634.6660 dan.zervoudakes@gmail.com https://www.drzwebdev.com/

Summary

- Fluent in HTML, (C|SA|LE)SS, and JavaScript (ES6, React, Node+Express, jQuery)
- Extensive experience with responsive design and development as related to a variety of web applications
- Proven track record of successfully driving each project through to completion

Technical Proficiencies

 Programming Languages, Frameworks and Content Management Systems:

ES6, React, Node+Express, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Photoshop JavaScript API, Node Slack API,

Grunt, Gulp, SQL Developer, Jade/Pug, WordPress

• eDetailing Packages: Veeva (Salesforce), iQ.mercury, Exploria

Software and Applications: Photoshop, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ

IDEA, Articulate Storyline, Illustrator, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, JIRA, Confluence, Litmus

• **Version Control Systems:** Git (GitHub, GitLab), Subversion (Cornerstone, Tortoise)

Conversion Optimization: Optimizely, Adobe Target

Professional Experience

Senior Front End Developer

HomeAdvisor, Golden, CO

July 2015 — Present

- Responsible for maintaining some of HomeAdvisor's most frequently visited web properties, including the My HomeAdvisor consumer portal and the Service Professional Acquisition path
- Effectively owned and drove all front end development pertaining to the company's brand new Category Expansion and Fixed Price Booking initiative
- Successfully drove a floor-wide initiative in switching conversion optimization platforms throughout the Consumer Site and Pro Site, ensuring zero conversion optimization downtime
- Spearheaded a research & development initiative incorporating modern desktop notifications on the consumer site using the native JavaScript Notification API
- Implemented a new system for narrowing down projects resulting in a 10 million dollar conversion win
- Architected and actively maintain a Node-based Slack bot that returns relevant data on our Java microservice instances in Dev. QA and Production
- Build and update web pages within a modular JSP codebase, leveraging the JSTL and various model attributes to dynamically display case-specific content, JavaScript and modern CSS/LESS
- Construct single page applications using a custom, in-house JavaScript framework harnessed within an Express test environment
- Experience interviewing, mentoring and conducting constructive code reviews with younger developers
- Conduct constructive code reviews with our development contractors
- Manipulate the front end with data extracted from and posted to RESTful APIs built within our Java microservices
- Create and monitor experiments within Optimizely and Adobe Target to assist the company with it's conversion optimization objectives and help build revenue in a meaningful way

Environment: HTML5, CSS3/LESS, JavaScript (raw, jQuery), Java, Jade/Pug, Adobe Target, Optimizely, Photoshop, Git, JIRA, IntelliJ IDEA, JSTL, Omniture, Grunt, Node Slack API, Litmus, Jade, SQL Developer

Senior Interactive Developer

Bristol-Myers Squibb (BMStudio), Plainsboro, NJ

June 2014 — July 2015

- Responsible for developing web-based interactive visual aids (IVAs) and animations on iPad with retina display while providing a high-quality user experience
- Set up a responsive widget for the ORENCIA® (abatacept) informational website turning static images into a sequential animation
- Developed a custom swiping mechanism to increase usability within Veeva iRep presentations on iOS
- Created a script that dynamically generates the appropriate slide references in a presentation and automatically updates applicable superscripts within the markup
- Built a script for use with the Photoshop JavaScript API which batch-exports slide thumbnail images at the appropriate dimensions and file format for use within the Veeva iRep shell
- Developed a jQuery "doubleTap" plugin for use in our visual aids
- Successfully converted multiple waves of European Exploria-based visual aids into Veeva iRep packages leveraging an in-house PHP engine
- Contributed to the development of a custom in-house JavaScript library for use within our IVAs
- Implemented a customizable "pinch-zoom" protocol for use within our IVAs via "iScroll"
- Effectively drive several projects simultaneously through successful implementation from start to finish while coordinating essential project tasks and estimates between the teams in Plainsboro, Tampa, and Europe
- Experience interacting directly with business partners and brand champions, helping to guide their understanding and expectations per project

Environment: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (raw, jQuery and a custom in-house library), PHP, Veeva iRep/Salesforce, Exploria, Photoshop, Illustrator, SharePoint, iOS, Mac OS X, Subversion (Cornerstone)

Multimedia Developer

Red Nucleus, Hamilton, NJ

April 2013 — June 2014

- Responsible for the timely delivery of web-based eLearning applications incorporating various forms of media including image sprites, audio and video for such high-profile clients as AstraZeneca, Karl Storz, Bayer Pharmaceuticals and Roche Diagnostics
- Provided the company's first digital detailing templates and working presentations for use within the iQ.mercury platform on iPad
- Constructed several templates for use throughout each application, controlled heavily by JavaScript and JSON objects
- Prepared application themes within and full documentation on using "Articulate Storyline" including known pitfalls and effective solutions to Storyline's inherent HTML5 output errors
- Converted the company's old flash-based eLearning programs into HTML and JavaScript applications
- Built full CSS themes for each project from scratch per brand guidelines and design comps
- Seamlessly supported the latest iOS platform as well as legacy browsers down to Internet Explorer 7 **Environment:** XHTML/XML, CSS, JavaScript (raw, jQuery and a custom in-house library), iQ.mercury, Photoshop, Illustrator, Articulate Storyline, iOS, Microsoft Windows, Git

Web and Interactive Developer

Freelance, Denver, Colorado

December 2012 — December 2016

Red Nucleus

- Periodically supplemented the company's development team in building web-based eLearning applications with quick turn-around
- Technologies used: XHTML/XML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop, iQ.mercury, Articulate Storyline, Git, GitLab

Tag Worldwide

- Built highly interactive eDetailing presentations for use within Veeva on the iPad
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Photoshop, Veeva iRep, Git

BlueModus

- Assisted the team with front end bug fixes on a health sciences website
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SASS, Gulp, Git, JIRA

StreamYourAd

- Responsible for the development of a startup company's HTML5- and CSS3-based website from scratch per design mockups
- Worked closely with the client to flesh out a coherent and consistently pleasing user experience
- Technologies used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (including jQuery), PHP

Grindstone.js / Shift.js

- Crafted a light-weight jQuery alternative with strikingly familiar syntax to streamline some of the more mundane JavaScript tasks in day-to-day development (Grindstone.js)
- Built a CSS3 transition/transform-based animations library (Shift.js)
- Constructed each with raw JavaScript, non-dependent on other libraries or plugins
- Incorporated a custom-build process via Node.js and Gulp so developers may select only the modules they require on a per-project basis

Graduated: May 26, 2012

- Published each library as a package on the "node package manager" (npm) website, https://www.npmjs.com/package/shiftjs and https://www.npmjs.com/package/grindstone
- Launched a mobile-first responsive website with full documentation and examples for each library

Education

University of Delaware, Newark, DE

Bachelors of Science in Management Information Systems

Concentration: Operations Management